A Guide to the Papers of the Secretary of the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia, 1998-2001
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Secretary of the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia 1998-2001
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-1/2/1.021
This collection consists of 4,200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred by Office of the Board of Visitors, The Rotunda, University of Virginia on 2002 October 21.
Biographical/Historical Information
During the time span of these papers, Alexander G. Gilliam, Jr. (1991- ) held the position of Secretary to the Board of Visitors.
Scope and Content Information
The papers consist of committee files and general records, including correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and related papers.
Contents List
- I: General Files 1994-2001
  - Audit Committee-Minutes 1998-2001 (Box 1)
  - Audit Committee-Correspondence 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Minutes 2000-2002 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Correspondence 2001-2002, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Correspondence 1999 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Correspondence 1999, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Educational Policy Committee-Minutes 2001-2002 (Box 2)
  - Educational Policy Committee-Correspondence 1998-2002, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee-Minutes 2001 (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee-Correspondence 1999-2001 (Box 2)
  - Executive Summaries 1999 (Box 2)
  - External Affairs Committee-Minutes 2000 (Box 2)
  - External Affairs Committee-Correspondence 1997-2002, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Finance Committee-Minutes 1998-2002 (Box 3)
  - Finance Committee 2000-2001, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Finance Committee-Correspondence 1999, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - U.Va. Investment Management Company Correspondence 1999, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Finance Committee-Correspondence 1999, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Finance Committee-Correspondence 1999 (Box 4)
  - U.Va.'s College at Wise Committee-Minutes 2000-2001 (Box 5)
  - U.Va.'s College at Wise 1998-1999 (Box 5)
  - Headline News about U.Va. 2001 (Box 5)
  - Pollock, Herbert C. 1995-2000 (Box 5)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2000 Jul-Dec, 1-3 of 5 (Box 5)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2000 Jul-Dec, 4-5 of 5 (Box 6)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2000 Jan-Jun, 1-2 of 4 (Box 6)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2000 Jan-Jun, 3-4 of 4 (Box 7)
  - Board Meetings-Open 1999, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Board Meetings-Executive Session 1998-1999 (Box 8)
  - Full Board Meeting 2001-2002 (Box 8)
  - Full Board Meetings 1998-1999, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Correspondence 2002 (Box 8)
  - Headline News about U.Va. 2001 Aug-Sept (Box 8)
  - Health Affairs Committee-Minutes 2001-2002 (Box 8)
  - Health Affairs Committee Correspondence and Minutes 2001 (Box 8)
  - Health Affairs Committee Correspondence 1999 Jun-Dec, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Health Affairs Committee Correspondence 1999 Jan-May, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Student Affairs and Athletics Committee-Minutes 1998-2002 (Box 9)
  - Student Affairs and Athletics Committee-Correspondence 1998-2002, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - U.Va's Investment Management Company-Minutes 2001-2002 (Box 10)
  - Institutional Profile of the University of Virginia 1995 (Box 10)
  - Targeting Excellence-U.Va. Self-Study 1994-1996 (Box 10)
  - Business Plan for the Proposed Campus of U.Va. at Doha 1998 (Box 10)
  - Business Plan for the Proposed Campus of U.Va. at Doha 1998 (Box 11)
  - Business Plan for the Proposed Campus of U.Va. at Doha 1999 (Box 11)
  - Report of Compliance-U.Va. Self-Study 1994-1996 (Box 11)
- II: Restricted Files 1999-2002 (Box 12)